ZACH BALDER

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT

617-610-6243

zmbalder@gmail.com

https://zachbalder.me

Greater Boston

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Python, Shell, Go

Frameworks/Libraries: Next.js, React, Vue, Tailwind CSS, 11ty, MUI, Shoelace, Express, Fastify, Hapi

Databases/ORMs: DynamoDB, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Supabase, Prisma, SQLite, Sequelize

Tooling: git, npm, Docker, Vite, eslint, prettier, ESBuild, Webpack

AWS: EC2, S3, CloudFront, API Gateway, Lambda, ELB/ALB, IAM

Cloud: Netlify, Cloudflare Pages, Vercel

Bug Bounty (HackerOne): Robinhood \$2k, Robinhood \$750, Glassdoor \$150

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Arts in Economics

Northwestern University

2013-2016 (incomplete)

CS courses

- Intro to Computer Programming
- Fundamentals of Computer Programming (C++)
- Intro to Artificial Intelligence (Python)

Interests

- Songwriting
- Music Production
- Saxophone
- Synthesizers/Sound Design
- Sci-fi
- Web Applications
- Computer Networking

ABOUT

I have 7 years experience as a software engineer, building web applications and software infrastructure. Previously, I was technical cofounder of a web design startup, the first full-time engineer hire at a video-chat startup, and software engineer on the cloud services team at a wireless internet provider. I've interviewed engineering candidates, led development teams, and operated in a customer support capacity. I'm currently looking for a front-end or full-stack web development role, working closely with a product team.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Contract Developer

Stealth startups

Sep 2023 - present

• Freelancing / full-stack web development

Cofounder & CTO

Wisiwig

Jun 2022 - Sep 2023 · 1 yr 4 mos

- Accepted into MassChallenge 2022 Early Stage program
- Managed technical sprint planning using GitHub Projects
- Built MVP Chrome extension for pilot program (featured on Chrome Store with >600 users)
- Built and deployed React application with API backend
- Translated Figma product designs into JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- · Set up analytics to provide quantitative evidence of user engagement for investor meetings
- Prepared investor demos to illustrate technical capabilities and product vision
- Assisted with email & social media marketing campaign and user discovery
- Provided technical updates during advisor meetings and attended networking events

Senior Software Engineer

Gatherly

Nov 2020 - Jun 2022 · 1 yr 8 mos

- Implemented event-wide video broadcast, a feature required by many customers
- Wrote unit, integration, and load tests to improve reliability and availability
- Created a staging environment, automated release process and rollbacks
- Introduced service logging to lower incident response times and improve customer support
- Secured cloud resources for SOC2 certification, leading to acquisition of enterprise customers
 Migrated frontend to support virutal events with >1000 attendees and onboard larger clients
- On-call for handling downtime incidents and troubleshooting issues with virtual events
- Reviewed resumes and screened engineering candidate profiles
- · Designed technical take-home exercise and conducted interviews

Software Engineer

Starry

Jun 2018 - Feb 2020 · 1 yr 9 mos

- Maintained internal projects that delivered internet to thousands of customers
- Developed encryption wrapper allowing our team to remove redundant code
- Built SNMP service to save technicians time when configuring field hardware
- Wrote full-coverage unit and integration tests
- Performed regular code reviews of pull requests across several repositories
- · Manually QA'd applications and committed bug fixes